#### Contact

roenap@aol.com 9166064900 (Mobile) roenap@aol.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rosemarievarner-rn-bsn-cnor-70ab6525 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Healthcare

Hospitals

Neurology

## Languages

English (Full Professional)

#### Certifications

**CNOR** 

Basic Life Support for Healthcare Providers (BLS)

#### Honors-Awards

Employee Excellence Award -Excellence In Leadership Platinum Award Winner Sigma Theta Tau International

# Rosemarie Varner RN, BSN, CNOR

Perioperative Nurse Consultant at Empiric Health West Sacramento, California

## Summary

Currently in a Clinical analyst consulting role in perioperative services implementing ways to lower healthcare costs in surgery without compromising clinical outcomes. My unique background encompasses staff level to director roles in the peri operative arena. I specialize in team development, project management, surgical support, product evaluations, equipment training, sales and new product launches. Experience in increasing revenue, surgical growth strategies, productivity enhancement, improving & supporting operational efficiencies, and process improvement functions. I am currently pursuing an Informatics MSN degree.

# Experience

Empiric Health
Perioperative Consultant/Clinical Analyst
August 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Salt Lake City, Utah

Provide clinical expertise, value analysis and recommendations to decrease clinical supply variation and promote standardization of surgical supplies and devices. Utilizing Proprietary analytical software, I am able to provide clinical data to support my findings through observations and drive change. Closely collaborate with OR directors, managers, clinical leads and supply chain to validate and support opportunities across various service lines. Monthly presentations to providers and Chief of surgery to engage and initiate changes.

Kaiser Permanente Perioperative Manager December 2015 - January 2019 (3 years 2 months) Vacaville, California

24 hr management of a Level 2 Trauma Center with over 10 service lines. Responsible for over 40 FTEs in an outpatient and inpatient OR .Actively involved in process improvement teams and lead unit based councils. Handled Staffing , recruitment , payroll supervision and staff development .Improved and sustained first case on time starts from 56% to 86%. Assisted in Total Joint standardization process , ERAS initiatives and SSI reduction bundles . Increased Total joint same day discharges from 36% to over 60% . Preference card standardization project implemented to reduce waste I, variation and duplication.

Bausch + Lomb
Surgical Product Consultant
June 2015 - December 2015 (7 months)

Sales & Support of Intraocular lenses, Surgical cataract & retina equipment, devices and instrumentation.

UC Davis Medical Center
3 years 10 months

Clinical Coordinator-Charge Nurse October 2011 - July 2015 (3 years 10 months) Sacramento, California Area

Managed, trained and supported the 24hr eye team at UC Davis medical center as well as coordinated the daily operations of 8 ORs in the trauma pod which included over 12 specialties. Eye surgeries included mainly retina, cornea, plastics, cataract, glaucoma and pediatric eye cases. Managed ophthalmology supplies and equipment, surgeon preference cards the training of new eye team members. Responsible for staffing the eye team call schedule and responding to emergencies. Supported timely turn over of rooms, facilitated breaks and lunches, case coverage and optimization daily readiness of the OR to minimize delays.

Interim Manager October 2011 - July 2015 (3 years 10 months) Main OR

Manage the daily operations and work flow of 8 operating rooms in the Main OR of a Level I Trauma Center. Services include our Robotic(DaVinci) suites, Trauma, General surgery, Gyn, Oncology, Urology and Transplant, Plastics and Ophthalmology.

Sutter Health
Director of Perioperative services-interim
February 2011 - October 2011 (9 months)

Managed 4 OR surgical suites, 1 endoscopy GI lab, pre-op, pacu, central processing and materials management teams. Responsible for increasing efficiency, maintaining high standards of patient care and improving patient satisfaction results measured by press-ganey. Responsible for over 50 FTEs and had 3 direct reports.

Columbia University Irving Medical Center OR RN-travel June 2010 - January 2011 (8 months) Greater New York City Area

Scrubbed various ophthalmology cases for 2 travel terms. Types of surgical cases included Anterior and Posterior Eye surgery such as cataracts, retina, glaucoma, ocular plastics and cornea surgeries.

John Muir Health Interim Director of nursing June 2008 - June 2010 (2 years 1 month)

Managed a high volume and high efficiency OR suite, Pacu, pre-op and central processing areas. Started as a travel charge RN and eventually assumed the interim DON position before the closure of the surgery center managed by HCA healthcare.

Cross Country TravCorps
Travel Nurse
March 2007 - June 2008 (1 year 4 months)

Bausch + Lomb
Sales Representative
July 2000 - July 2005 (5 years 1 month)

Began my career as a Clinical application specialist (sales support role) and eventually promoted into a Senior surgical sales position responsible for managing a vast area of accounts in the DE, MD, and VA areas selling bausch & lomb's surgical capital equipment in operating rooms. Called on Hospitals, Administrators, Materials managers, CFO's, Surgeons, surgery centers, clinics and government medical centers. Exceeded quotas annually, proven track record, achieved sales awards and trips.

## Education

The College of New Rochelle

Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1992 - 1996)